# **MATHIUS JOHNSON**

## CONTACT

# **SUMMARY**

I am a motivated web developer with experience building template modules using HTML, CSS and JS. I also have Full Stack experience building apps in a React with Redux Front End and a Typescript Express Back End. With strong collaboration skills, a passion for problem solving and the tenacity to keep going no matter the pressure, I want to solve big problems with others and build beautiful apps along the way.

# **EMPLOYMENT**

## Lighthouse Labs

Remote

Project Evaluator · Dec. 2020 to Current

- Provides constructive feedback to students for completed projects in the 12 week Web Development Bootcamp
- Evaluation of javascript fundamentals in projects built with node.js, express.js, and react.js using custom hooks and reducer

#### **WXM**

Remote

Front End Web/Interface Developer · Nov. 2020 to Current

- Use of HTML, CSS with Tailwind and Bootstrap, jQuery DOM manipulation to build modules in C# DNN's 2sxc Content Editor
- Development of a keen eye for detail and more advanced techniques with html, styling and jquery with modals and carousels

## Lighthouse Labs

Apprentice Mentor · Nov. 2020 to Current

- Part Time position responding to student assistance requests for the Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp at Lighthouse Labs.
- Assisted students learning how to write and debug their code while building web applications in Vanilla JS and JQuery with Express.js

## Landscape Maintenance Supervisor

North Vancouver, BC

Carefree Greenery · July 2017 to Mar. 2020

- Lead landscape horticulturist in crew of 2-4 people.
- Utilized time management tending to high end properties in the fast-paced environment of downtown Vancouver.
- Managed weekly maintenance for each crew member with clear direction and guidance.

## Certified Yoga Instructor

Edmonton, Alberta

Self-Employed · Dec. 2014 to July 2019

- Increased awareness of mind-body perception to maximize human potential.
- Maintained composure and communication while working under intense conditions.

# **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, TDD, Typescript

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES AND ENVIRONMENTS: NodeJS, ReactJS, Rails, Ajax, Express, EJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, ActiveRecord, SASS, Socket.IO, Redux, Angular, Vuejs, Tailwind

SYSTEMS, CMS & DATABASES: Netifly, CircleCi, Heroku, SQL

TESTING: RSpec, Jest, Mocha & Chai, TDD, BDD, Capybara, Poltergeist, Phantom, Cypress

## **EDUCATION**

LighthouseLabs · July 2020 to Oct. 2020 Diploma of Full Stack Web Development, specializing in Javascript with Intro to Ruby

BrainStation · May 2020 to June 2020 Certificate in HTML and CSS

Lighthouse Labs · May 2020 to June 2020 Certificate in Intro to Front End with Javascript

Industry Training Authority
Jan. 2018 to Mar. 2020
3rd year Red Seal Apprentice in
Landscape Horticulture

# **PROJECTS**

Kuhner Shaker Digital Booth Nov. 2020 to Jan. 2020

- SPA using HTML, TailwindCSS and jQuery to build template modules in C#'s DNN 2sxc Content Editor.
- Multiple modals and modals within modals created, as well as a semi-complex filter product function using jQuery and bootstrap modals

#### Stack Social Network Sept. 2020 to Current

- Game-ified social network connecting web developers with mentors using Typescript and Javascript functional components in React.js, express.js with PostgreSQL, and persistent data.
- Custom hooks implemented with useReducer and useContext for Gatsby.js

Open Source Contributions (MatterMost) Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020

- Migrating Client-side chat application from Javascript to Typescript
- Introduction to using Docker and Typescript

#### Scheduler

Aug. 2020 to Sept. 2020

• Week-long SPA interview scheduler project using React with PostgreSQL, persistent data, and websocket.

#### Food Ordering App Aug. 2020 to Aug. 2020

- Week-long group project building a SPA Food Ordering App Using Jquery, SQL, and AJAX
- Communicates to restaurant owner and users via Twilio.
- Major contributions HTML and CSS layout, Admin interface, jquery routes with AJAX for Twilio communication, database building and routes.